Hello
Today I will show you how to bake a student cake
[Vignette]
I have pulled so much to record this video
Because I really don't want to tread on any toes,
On the contrary, just give inspiration, joy
and the feeling that one can treat yourself
A delicious student celebration anyway.
But I still want to take the opportunity to complain,
For all of you who take the student this year,
But don't get the chance to celebrate the one you want.
So damn boring hopefully you can take it again soon.
Anyway, I'm here today to show you
How to bake your own student cake.
From scratch, how to bake your own student cake.
What I start with is the cake base itself.
For it you need ...
Eggs, powdered sugar, wheat flour, cornstarch or potato flour,
vanilla sugar and baking powder.
What I start with is whisk together powdered sugar and eggs
Really white and puffy, with an electric whisk.
[Background Music]
So there
Now that the batter is wonderfully white and fluffy,
Then it's time to aim down the dry ingredients.
And those dry ingredients are wheat flour,
potato flour or cornstarch,
vanilla sugar and baking powder.
To just have a starch in the batter for his cake base,
Make it extra soft and fluffy.
How to gently turn this together into a smooth batter with a lollipop.
Make sure to scrape off the edges and get all the ingredients.
I feel the batter how fluffy it is
And how good this cake base will be.
So I bring out my lined spring form,
I have shown this in many videos before, so I think I don't show it.
Then just pour the batter into the spring shape.
Now this cake base should be baked in the lower part of the oven
at 175 degrees for about 40 minutes
Or until it is simply packed.
Again, it is super important to remember that
All ovens are different.
Time statements in prescriptions, whether it is mine or others,
is just a guideline.
One must get to know one's own oven
and simply take a little look at the cake,
to know if it is finished or not.
While my cake base is both baked and swallows,
I take the opportunity to make my fillings.
After all, there are three fillings in this cake,
But don't let it deter you,
Because there are three super -simple fillings
Which does not require much effort at all.
First out, we have the vanilla cream.
To make it, do you need:
Whipped cream, milk, powdered sugar,
cornstarch or potato flour,
an egg yolk, vanilla powder and butter.
What I start with is to have in all ingredients
In addition to the butter, in a saucepan
let it heat up and thicken on medium heat,
Before I have in the butter.
And when you heat on this vanilla cream,
is it super important that you heat it on
low to medium heat and stirring all the time,
So it does not burn.
And now it's time for filling number two,
which is a raspberry compote.
This raspberry compote will balance up with
A lot of lovely acidity, against all this cute in the cake.
What you need to make the raspberry compote is:
Frozen raspberries, powdered sugar, agar agar powder
One only has in all the ingredients in a saucepan
And then we heat this until the sugar crystals have melted.
Now is the time to do the third and final filling,
Namely milk chocolate truffle.
To make it, you only need three ingredients:
Milk chocolate, butter and whipped cream.
What I start with is to chop the milk chocolate.
That's how
Then just have in the milk chocolate in a heat -resistant bowl
And together with the milk chocolate, I also have the butter.
Over this I will pour hot whipped cream.
I pour the cream into a saucepan,
It's not so much cream,
So you really have to be on guard,
And don't go away and do something else.
You just heat this just until it's about to start boiling,
Then you remove the saucepan from the heat.
Now also my milk chocolate truffle is ready,
It should stand and cool at room temperature.
If you set it in the fridge, it will not stay creamy and spreadable at all,
So we can fill the cake with it, but instead get pretty firm.
As soon as it has cooled I will split my cake base
and fill my cake with all these three lovely fillings,
cover with whipped cream
And then we will make this cake look like a student cap.
Now my cake base has cooled and I will divide it into three parts.
The easiest way I think you can split a cake base on,
is to first mark so you know that they will be about as thick.
Then I start on the top mark
and gently cut towards the center.
The knife should only be moved back and forth
while rotating your cake base.
Try to keep it as straight as possible,
to get as straight as possible.
The lower part of the cake base,
I shovel it over on a cake dish,
Because I don't want to serve the cake on a grid.
The first layer filling, it is raspberry compote.
I just click out the raspberry compote like this.
Next in turn we have the lovely homemade vanilla cream,
Which you just click on top.
Then just go on with the next bottom.
Make sure they lay edge to edge, around the whole cake.
So it is important not to place the cake in the middle of the cake dish,
Without a little more to the edge,
so we can fit with a small cap screen
to this student cap.
Now I am happy with the foundation
And what remains now is whisk really fluffy cream,
As we will cover the cake with,
before we go in with the marzipan.
The secret behind a really fluffy whipped cream,
is that it should be a refrigerator shell
And preferably of as high fat as you can only find.
Then you start whisking at a little lower speed,
Then when you see that it is getting really bubbly and foamy,
Then you can increase the speed a little until you get soft tops.
This is what I mean when I say
That the whipping cream should have soft tops.
It should be compliant, glossy, not at all grainy
Because if it is already grainy and a little firmer when you have whipped it,
then you don't have much margin at all to work with
When to cover the cake with whipped cream,
Because we will be doing it even more,
And then it becomes like stirring in the cream.
Now I will cover the cake in whipped cream
And usually when making, for example, a princess cake,
Then you want to get that dome -shaped cake,
We don't want that today,
Because it should look like a student cap.
So I will work a little more after the straight look,
The easiest way, I think,
is to shovel on a bunch of cream
on top of the cake.
I'll see if I need the rest late,
But we start like this.
Slowly but surely you scrape whipped cream on the edges of the cake.
For when it comes to both White Lady and Princess Cake,
So you don't want much whipped cream all around,
However, at the top, it may be a generous layer.
But it is also personal.
If you want to be a little more sparse when it comes to the cream,
So you can definitely be.
Now this cake should stand in the refrigerator to sit down,
The cream should be a little more firm,
While we roll out the white marzipan,
that will cover the entire cake.
The excess cream all around,
we don't have to worry about right now.
As soon as it has been in the fridge and become a little firmer,
Then you can much easier to dry it,
than now, when it's just beaten.
Now it's time to roll the white marzipan.
I know that rolling of marzipan may be a bit of a concern for most of them,
But with the right material and the right technology
So there are no wonder.
First, you need to have more marzipan than you need
to cover the cake itself.
Because if you have much more than you need,
Then you can pull out the marzipan a little and smooth it out,
Without the marzipan cracking.
My second tip is to knead the marzipan properly,
Before you roll it out, because then it becomes much more flexible and compliant.
And to get as smooth rolling on his marzipan as possible,
So I have two tips.
The first is to get one of these Kavling's mat.
You know that I am not much for gadgets in the kitchen.
But if there is something that I actually think you should buy,
Then it is such a rolling rug.
It facilitates something huge.
Partly it has sizes,
So you know how much to roll,
so you don't roller too large or too small
Because it gets so hard then when turning on the marzipan over the cake
[Camilla with distorted and funny voice:] "Oh no, if I only had two inches to"
Then it is so that when you roll on such a rug,
Do not need to lift the marzipan with your hands later
Without you can only lift the entire carpet and turn it over the cake,
So the marzipan goes off in a neat way without cracking.
Of course, I put a link to such a rolling rug in the description,
If you are eager to get one yourself.
My second tip is to use cornstarch when rolling
Do you use icing sugar,
Then the icing sugar will eventually melt and it gets sticky.
While the cornstarch, the marzipan and the rolling are dry.
I have some cornstarch on the rolling mat
And on the marzipan itself.
Then I roll in different directions,
Make sure to turn on the marzipan all the time,
so that I don't roll in just one direction
and gets a thick side and a narrow side.
As soon as you feel it starts stuck,
Can you have more cornstarch.
When you roll the marzipan you can sometimes get small air bubbles
You should not leave them.
Go in with a toothpick, grill stick or a needle,
or something else vassly you have at home
And crack them before continuing to roll.
Then I think it is very important that the marzipan is not too thick.
The worst thing I know is eating a marzipan cake
With far too much marzipan.
No more than that.
At the end I usually only take a few lightweight rods
where I do not give any pressure on the rolling pin itself,
but only to even out the surface itself.
Before I have on the marzipan,
Should I just make sure to wipe away excess whipped cream on the edge.
So this is such a nervous moment, silicone mat or not.
You just want it to be good.
Okay ... three, two, one, drive
I was aiming a little oblique, I do this ... so
Now we take one corner at a time, smooth out, pull.
Smooth out, pull.
Until the whole cake is covered,
Without a lot of creases.
Will be messy now, but as I said, we wipe it up later.
The focus now is to get to the marzipan nicely.
Press it around the entire cake,
You want it to attach properly.
Let this take time
And make sure to have completely dry hands when you do this.
For will moisture on the marzipan,
Then it will be sticky.
Now you can take the opportunity to shape the cake a little.
Really straight sides and a slightly flatter surface.
Then you go in gently with a pizza slicer or knife
And just cut off the abundance.
I don't usually go too close to the cake from the beginning,
Without me starting quite far out,
And run the finer later.
Just cut where you see.
The worst thing is if you happen to cut too much, because you thought you saw.
because a student cap is not straight,
Because then you look like ...
What is the name of that cartoon figure with a round helmet
Anyway...
We'll make this look like a real hat.
Then I do, with the help of different kitchen utensils,
with different cutlery and so,
So I only do like little folds.
It is important to do this while the cake has not gone into the fridge again.
Because as soon as you put the cake into the refrigerator
so the marzipan will start to solidify
And then you can't do this.
So little random folds,
Rather that it is irregular as a student cap actually looks,
than to do exactly the same on both sides.
It should be a bit asymmetrical.
I will actually not put it in the cooler,
Until I am completely clear, if I would like to change the shape somewhat.
But what it's time for now is to use Smartt ...
[Beep]
Smartt ..
Black marzipan, to make a strip around the whole cap,
And also to make a cap screen.
Wonder if it's called so
So I hate black marzipan, it has such a strange texture.
It is because they need to have so much color.
Just black marzipan
So now we go with lots of black ...
[Beep]
[Camilla laughs]
May starch here ...
Pretty much indeed.
Then I roll it out.
This strip needs to be
Much longer than the perimeter around the cake.
And now we add another layer of marzipan on the cake
I who don't like a thick layer of marzipan ...
I prefer...
a little wider than one centimeter.
I just had to wash away all the color from my hands
So I don't scratch the cake.
But I won't dry my hands completely dry
because one needs some water
to make the black strip attach.
So I iron some moisture on the marzipan with my hands
Then I just take this strip ...
Starts from the front
And gently puts it along the entire cake.
That's how
I try to attach the ends a little neatly with each other at the back
and there the strip is ready
And now it's time to make the screen itself.
Now the idea is to just roll out this
to an arbitrary form
that have a little width and a little height,
for we will not cut to this one
until yes put it next to the cap itself, on the barrel.
But what I will do now is that I cut a little bent.
There somewhere I want it.
So just press so it follows the shape of the cake.
Then you cut to a small cap shape.
And now we come to the final decoration
This little one ...
Place it in the middle of the yellow circle
And then just push the blue ball there,
So that it gets a little flat.
Don't take too much water,
If you do that, there is a risk that it will just be lousy and fall off.
It really is a delicate boundary between moisten
and make something wet.
Is there even someone who has checked this far
And that has remained, to see the final result.
If you are one of those who look all the way to the last second of the video,
So you have to write it down in the comments section.
But this is how the final momentary cake looks like.
How nice?
You can make it how spicy and how simple as you just want.
This is a very simple look.
But if you want to add marzipan roses,
write with chocolate, just go bananas
No matter how you do,
So you will find the link to the recipe down in the description.